Guide to the Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement Collection, 1946-1985 RL.00223
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement collection
1946-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China
RL.00223
3.5 Linear Feet
Produced mostly by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China. The material was found in a cinema company office in Henan province, China. Collection of film advertisements and transcripts of Chinese documentary films and newsreels that spans the years 1946 to 1985; bulk of items are transcripts for documentary films and newsreels from the Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976. Dating of the 1946 item is questionable. All documents are in Chinese. Arranged into the following series: Advertisements and Film Description Series; Documentary and Newsreel Scripts Series; Feature Filmscripts Series; and Newspaper Clipping Scrapbook Series. Topics include industry, agriculture, the economy, military matters, education, public health care, medicine and science, as well as political movements, foreign relations, cultural and sporting events. Collection also contains a group of printed advertisements and other publicity for Chinese and foreign films, plays, opera, and local performances. Finally, collection includes 8 master microfilm reels for the collection.
1758 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Chinese Filmscript and Advertisement Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2005.
Historical Note
Produced mostly by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of China, documentary films and newsreels were two of the major mass media and communication channels in China from the 1950s through 1970s. They covered all aspects of social activities, though the emphasis was on developments and achievements in the building of a socialist country. In order to reach even broader public audiences, government agents produced and printed the transcripts and shot lists for the films and sent them to cities and rural areas. Few of these printed materials have survived due to the poor quality of the paper upon which they were printed. The material in this collection was found in a cinema company office in Henan province, China.
Collection Overview
The collection of film advertisements and transcripts of Chinese documentary films and newsreels spans the years 1946 to 1985, although the bulk of the items in the collection are transcripts for the documentary films and newsreels from the Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976. It should also be noted that the dating of the 1946 item is questionable. All documents in the collection are in Chinese. The collection is arranged into the following series: Advertisements and Film Description Series, 1953-1966 and undated; Documentary and Newsreel Scripts Series, 1946 (?)-1985 and undated; Feature Filmscripts Series, undated; and Newspaper Clipping Scrapbook Series, 1950-1959 and undated. Topics include industry, agriculture, the economy, military matters, education, public health care, medicine and science, as well as political movements, foreign relations, cultural and sporting events. Most of the documentary filmscripts are short, focusing on a specific subject or event, whereas newsreel scripts are numbered sequentially within each year and cover multiple topics or events. During the Cultural Revolution, documentary films and newsreels were powerful and popular propaganda tools for patriotism, nationalism, Chairman Mao, the Communist Party, and socialist construction, and served political purposes.
In this collection, there is also a group of printed advertisements and other publicity for Chinese and foreign films, plays, opera, and local performances. This collection is valuable for studies of contemporary Chinese culture, the Cultural Revolution, history and politics, communist propaganda, and mass media.
Parts of this collection have been digitized and are available to the Duke University Community in the following database: Chinese Film and Newsreel Scripts from the Cultural Revolution Online
A separate searchable index is available at: Film title index of Chinese filmscript and advertisement collection
The collection was microfilmed for broader access in 2006, and the original master copies of the microfilm are in the final box of the collection.
China -- History -- 1949-1976 -- Sources; China -- History -- 1949-1976; Propaganda, Communist -- China; Documentary films -- China -- History and criticism; China -- Politics and government -- 1949-1976; China -- History -- Cultural Revolution -- 1966-1976; Communication in politics -- China; Communication -- Political aspects -- China; Mass media -- China
- Advertisements and Film Description Series, 1953-1966 and undated, 1 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Film advertisements and publicity materials for Chinese documentary films, Chinese feature films, and foreign films that were imported mostly from communist countries, such as Vietnam, North Korea, Romania, and Albania. They include summaries of the story, main characters, publicity topics, terms of use, text for blackboard postings or broadcasting, and discussion questions. Also includes some posters, performance schedules and programs for films, plays, opera, local performances, etc. Some of these have illustrations and screen shots. Arranged by title, then chronologically.
  - 宣 传 资 料 Xuan Chuan Zi Liao, 1953-1966 and undated, 8 folders
    - 金银滩, 1953 September 21 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Film Director: 凌子风
      Production Year: 1953
    - 罗马尼亚人民共和国（罗马尼亚）, 1954 December 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 列奥尼达·瓦尔拉莫夫
      Production Year: 1954
    - 平原游击队, 1956 January 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 武兆堤、苏里
      Production Year: 1955
    - 神秘的伴侣, 1956 January 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 林农、朱文顺
    - 水乡的春天, 1956 January 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 谢晋
    - 欢乐的歌舞, 1956 April 3 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 石岚
      Production Year: 1956
    - 小熊和烟斗, 1956 April 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 亚历山大·伊万诺夫
    - 罗马, 11点钟（意大利）, 1956 April 24 (Box 1)
      Film Director: G·D·桑蒂斯
    - 山城春色, 1956 June 7 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 尼古拉伊·萨尼施维里
      Production Year: 1954/1956
    - 马兰花开, 1956 June 19 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 李恩杰
    - 扑不灭的火焰, 1956 June 23 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 伊琳
    - 这决不是小事情, 1956 August 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 严寄洲
    - 蔚蓝色的节日, 1956 September 26 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 弗拉其米尔·西斯
      Production Year: 1953/1955
    - 祝福, 1956 October 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 桑弧
    - 庵堂认母, 1956 November 23 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 杨小仲
    - 庵堂相会, 1956 December 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 俞仲英
    - 秋翁遇仙记, 1956 December 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 吴永刚
    - 受气丈夫, 1956 December 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 瓦尔孔宜·卓尔丹
    - 母亲, 1956 December 30 (Box 1)
    - 谁是凶手, 1956 December 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 方徨
    - 称心如意（匈牙利）, 1957 January 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 马克·加罗来
    - 刘巧儿, 1957 January 13 (Box 1)
    - 真假儿媳妇（捷克）, 1957 January 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·再芒
    - 小白旗的风波, 1957 January 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 高衡
    - 上甘岭, 1957 January 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 沙蒙、林杉
    - 魔鬼集团（东德）, 1957 January 21 (Box 1)
      Film Director: C·巴尔豪斯
    - 游园惊梦, 1957 February 15 (Box 1)
    - 306号案件（苏联）, 1957 February 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 雷巴阔夫
    - 恭贺新禧, 1957 February 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王映东、毛羽、马德昌、吴向之
    - 年青的日子（捷克）, 1957 February 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 马·弗利奇
    - 家, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 陈西禾、叶明
    - 妈妈要我出嫁, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 黄粲
    - 国庆10点钟, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 吴天
    - 落水记, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 周峰
    - 匹克威克先生外传（英国）, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 诺伊尔·兰格里
      Production Year: 1957
    - 旋转木马（匈牙利）, 1957 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 法布里·卓尔丹
    - 皮包, 1957 March 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王岚
    - 三个孩子和小狗（捷克）, 1957 March 4 (Box 1)
      Film Director: j·外斯
    - 搜书院, 1957 March 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 徐韬
    - 小伙伴, 1957 March 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 葛鑫
    - 不拘小节的人, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 白穆
    - 关不住, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 张辛实
    - 暴风中的雄鹰, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王逸
    - 铁道游击队, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 赵明
    - 骄傲的将军, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 特伟
    - 胖嫂回娘家, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 虞哲光
    - 三个邻居, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 岳路
    - 机智的山羊, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 万超尘
    - 金耳环与铁锄头, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 徐秉铎
    - 马歇尔,欢迎你!（西班牙）, 1957 March 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 贝尔兰加·路易斯·加西亚
    - 沙皇与木匠（东德）, 1957 March 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 汉·牟列尔
    - 群英会, 1957 March 21 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 岭范
    - 我的生活（捷克）, 1957 March 23 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 瓦·克尔什卡
    - 战友们一路平安（朝鲜）, 1957 March 23 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 郑准采
    - 达利波尔（捷克）, 1957 March 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 瓦茨拉夫·格尔什卡
    - 战斗里成长, 1957 March 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 严寄洲，孙民
    - 十五贯, 1957 March 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 陶金
    - 跟踪（南斯拉夫）, 1957 March 29 (Box 1)
      Film Director: S. · 斯克里舍
    - 他的真名实姓（东德）, 1957 April 1 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 柯恩拉· 渥路夫
    - 宋景诗, 1957 April 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 郑君里
    - 暗无天日（日本）, 1957 April 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 今井正
    - 狼（日本）, 1957 April 29 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 新藤兼人
    - 漂亮的朋友（法国）, 1957 May 7 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 路易达肯
    - 我们美好的日子（埃及）, 1957 May 14 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 哈默· 哈里姆
    - 蝴蝶杯, 1957 May 7 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王家乙
    - 罗汉钱, 1957 May 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 顾而已
    - 苦难情侣（意大利）, 1957 May 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: C·利萨尼
    - 缩影（日本）, 1957 May 30 (Box 1)
    - 激战前夜, 1957 May 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王冰、冯毅夫
    - 攻城计（南斯拉夫）, 1957 June 12 (Box 1)
      Film Director: R· 诺瓦高维茨
    - 白菜主任（东德）, 1957 June 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: G· 列什
    - 她的爱（缅甸）, 1957 June 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 吴千吞
    - 沙道城的故事（朝鲜）, 1957 June 20 (Box 1)
    - 椰林曲, 1957 June 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王为一
    - 李时珍, 1957 June 26 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 沈浮
    - 影子（波兰）, 1957 June 26 (Box 1)
      Film Director: J· 卡瓦列洛维奇
    - 英雄城（保加利亚）, 1957 June 28 (Box 1)
      Film Director: H· 科拉保夫，孟道夫
    - 火（香港）, 1957 July 4 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 左凡
    - 华沙美人鱼（波兰）, 1957 July 4 (Box 1)
    - 风山疑案（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1957 July 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: J· 谢克文斯
    - 女篮5号, 1957 July 10 (Box 1)
    - 青年先锋（苏联）, 1957 July 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 叶果诺夫
    - 阴云（新加坡）, 1957 July 17 (Box 1)
    - 桑弟与维娜（泰国）, 1957 July 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 拉克 潘俩拉春，罗伯尔特 戈· 霍尔德
    - 米（日本）, 1957 July 24 (Box 1)
    - 章西女皇（印度）, 1957 July 27 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 梭拉伯· 莫地
    - 一个跛子（印度尼西亚）, 1957 August 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 卡达· 斯
    - 凤凰之歌, 1957 August 3 (Box 1)
    - 陈三五娘, 1957 August 3 (Box 1)
    - 阿福寻宝记, 1957 August 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 徐苏灵
    - 原来就是你（罗马尼亚）, 1957 August 9 (Box 1)
      Film Director: P· 卡里涅斯库
    - 李二嫂改嫁, 1957 August 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 刘国权
    - 向何处去（黎巴嫩）, 1957 August 19 (Box 1)
    - 查雅布拉纳（印度尼西亚）, 1957 August 19 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 戈多· 苏加迪
    - 雁荡山, 1957 August 28 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 岑范
    - 让我来办（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1957 September 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: S·弗伊奇
    - 四海之内皆兄弟（法国）, 1957 September 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: C·贾克
    - 杜十娘, 1957 September 7 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 许珂
    - 希望号战舰（保加利亚）, 1957 September 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: K·伊林切夫
    - 革命的前奏（苏联）, 1957 September 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: E·吉甘
    - 初欢（苏联）, 1957 September 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·巴索夫
    - 如此人生（意大利）, 1957 September 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 亚历山大·巴赛蒂
    - 金发公主（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1957 September 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: J·杜德赛克，H· 泰尔洛瓦
    - 撒谎的鼻子（罗马尼亚）, 1957 September 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 云·波比斯库·高波
    - 玛格丹娜的遭遇(苏联), 1957 September 27 (Box 1)
      Film Director: T·阿布拉德吉
    - 小木克（东德）, 1957 October 19 (Box 1)
      Film Director: W·什塔乌捷
    - 血的河流（阿根廷）, 1957 October 19 (Box 1)
      Film Director: H·D·卡利尔
    - 仇恨的旋风（苏联）, 1957 October 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·卡拉托卓夫
    - 借年, 1957 October 25 (Box 1)
    - 上海姑娘, 1957 November 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 成荫
    - 雾都孤儿（英国）, 1957 November 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: D·李恩
    - 柏林情话（东德）, 1957 November 18 (Box 1)
      Film Director: G·克列茵
    - 裂痕（匈牙利）, 1957 December 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: L·拉诺吉
    - 乘风破浪, 1957 December 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 孙瑜、蒋君超
    - 芦笙恋歌, 1957 December 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 于彦夫
    - 地下尖兵, 1957 December 18 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 武兆堤
    - 红颜劫（香港）, 1957 December 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 朱克、江泓
    - 法官（东德）, 1958 January 3 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 马·海皮克
    - 不爱清洁的孩子（波兰）, 1958 January 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: E·司徒尔利斯
    - 五更寒, 1958 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 五支歌（东德）, 1958 January 25 (Box 1)
    - 红莲花（罗马尼亚）, 1958 January 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: G·托比阿斯
    - 牧人之子, 1958 February 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 朱文顺、德·广布道尔基
    - 战斗的童年（苏联）, 1958 February 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 高鲁布
    - 洞箫横吹, 1958 February 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 鲁韧
    - 幸福, 1958 February 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 天然、傅超武
    - 魔棍（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1958 April 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 颇列斯阔特
    - 风筝（中法联合摄制）, 1958 April 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王家乙、罗歇·比果
    - 生活的浪花, 1958 April 17 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 陈怀皑
      Production Year: 1958
    - 传奇英雄（东德，法国联合摄制）, 1958 April 19 (Box 1)
      Film Director: G·菲利浦，J·伊文恩
    - 十月的光芒（苏联）, 1958 April 25 (Box 1)
    - 历史的教训（苏联）, 1958 April 26 (Box 1)
      Film Director: C·柯洛索夫
    - 静静的世界（法国）, 1958 May 5 (Box 1)
    - 汉尼巴先生（匈牙利）, 1958 May 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: Z·法布里
    - 忏悔（匈牙利）, 1958 May 14 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·凯莱蒂
    - 红孩子, 1958 May 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 苏里
    - 大风浪里的小故事, 1958 May 30 (Box 1)
    - 失业的自由（西德）, 1958 May 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: A·M·拉本拿尔特
    - 魔鬼的深渊（罗马尼亚）, 1958 May 30 (Box 1)
    - 家庭争执（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1958 July 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·巴尔契克
    - 水库上的歌声, 1958 July 25 (Box 1)
    - 诗人（苏联）, 1958 July 30 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·巴尔涅特
    - 科伦上尉（东德）, 1958 August 9 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 斯·杜多夫
    - 探亲记, 1958 August 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 谢添、桑夫
    - 被遗弃的人（墨西哥）, 1958 August 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 爱弥略·番南台斯
    - 英雄虎胆, 1958 September 4 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 严寄洲、郝光
    - 危险的生活（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1958 September 4 (Box 1)
      Film Director: J·瓦伊斯
    - 红与黑（法国，意大利联合摄制）, 1958 September 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: C·乌当·拉哈
    - 幸福的磨房（罗马尼亚）, 1958 September 6 (Box 1)
      Film Director: V·伊里乌
    - 情探, 1958 September 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 黄祖模
    - 平凡的事业, 1958 September 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 林扬
    - 患难之交, 1958 September 20 (Box 1)
    - 金铃传, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 2
      Film Director: 刘沛然
    - 钢花遍地开, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 21
      Film Director: 张天赐、啸马、石灵
    - 深山里的菊花, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 32
    - 列宁的故事（苏联）, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 37
      Film Director: C·尤特凯维奇
    - 被侮辱与被迫害的人（法国）, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 42
      Film Director: G·阿其门
    - 飞腾的广西, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 53
    - 山上开运河, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 54
      Film Director: 雷震霖
    - 不尽长江滚滚来, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 57
    - 油船火焰, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 69
      Film Director: 毛羽
    - 在伯爵的废墟上（苏联）, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 77
      Film Director: B·斯库伊宾
    - 英雄赶派克, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 82
    - 红叶（白俄罗斯）, 1959 (Box 1)
      No. 188
      Film Director: B·科尔什萨勃林
    - 胡志明主席革命活动片断（越南）, 1960 (Box 1)
      No. 165
    - 再生记, 1960 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 刘群
      Production Year: 1960
    - 12次列车, 1960 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 郝光、张岚
    - 东风第一枝, 1960 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 曾未之
    - 木木（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 167
    - 伊万娜（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 168
    - 生活从此开始（东德）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 174
    - 排演在继续, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 178
    - 慧眼丹心, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 186
    - 突破乌江, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 187
      Film Director: 李舒田、李昴
      Production Year: 1961
    - 繁荣的德意志民主共和国（东德）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 191
      Production Year: 1959
    - 罗米欧.朱丽叶和黑暗（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 194
    - 为了扣.卡什巴尔的生命（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 199
    - 游侠纳斯列金（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 200
    - 谢寥莎（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 201
    - 农村的妇女（墨西哥）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 203
    - 王老五添丁（香港）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 207
      Film Director: 胡小峰
    - 他们在战斗, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 217
      Film Director: 陈岗
    - 红色娘子军, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 223
    - 太阳的小客人, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 229
      Film Director: 邬强、徐景达
    - 勐垅沙, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 234
      Film Director: 王苹、袁先
    - 延安生活散记, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 339
    - 中国工农红军生活片断, 1961 (Box 1)
    - 51号兵站, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 343
      Film Director: 刘琼
    - 被开垦的处女地（下集）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 356
    - 可怜天下父母心（香港）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 359
      Film Director: 楚原
    - 生活的道路（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 360
      Film Director: 阿布时依托夫
    - 不屈服的人（白俄罗斯）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 363
      Film Director: 舒里囊
    - 春雷, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 366
      Film Director: 凌子风、侣朋
    - 山鹰（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 367
      Film Director: B·伊万诺夫
    - 更高原则（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 368
    - 穷街（保加利亚）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 369
      Film Director: X·皮斯科夫
    - 斗争的序曲（朝鲜）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 370
      Film Director: 姜兴植
    - 世纪同龄人（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 371
      Film Director: C·萨姆桑诺夫
    - 一个妇女会员的故事（朝鲜）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 372
      Film Director: 孙武彪
    - 复活（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 374
      Film Director: M·什维茨尔
    - 珍珠（墨西哥）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 375
      Film Director: E·费南台兹
    - 空邮（东德）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 376
      Film Director: 克劳斯·乔其
    - 白夜（苏联）, 1961 (Box 1)
      No. 377
      Film Director: 贝里也夫
    - 勐垅沙, 1961 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王苹，袁先
    - 春雷, 1961 November 2 (Box 1)
    - 海蒂（瑞士）, 1961 November 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: L·考门西尼
    - 少女的春天（苏联）, 1961 December 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·道尔芒
    - 人们到处生活（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1961 December 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: J·卡尼巴尔，S·斯卡尔斯基
    - 台风 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 陈冀
    - 织锦 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 蒋伟
    - 自动化的机械（苏联）, 1960 (Box 1)
      Film Director: K·巴巴什金
    - 飞往宇宙之前（苏联）, 1959 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·莫尔甘什切伦
    - 车床的喜悦, 1961 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 苏伟
    - 春催桃李, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 290
    - 智擒眼睛蛇（苏联）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 379
      Film Director: 瓦西亚耶夫
    - 鞋匠（波兰）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 380
    - 菲利和玛莉的故事（匈牙利）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 382
      Film Director: 洛尔特列尔
    - 摩尔人的遗嘱（苏联）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 384
      Film Director: 采哈诺夫斯基，采哈诺夫斯卡娅
    - 山鹰之歌（阿尔巴尼亚）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 385
      Film Director: 奥泽罗夫
    - 勇士的传说（苏联）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 386
    - 万木春, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 389
    - 李双双, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 391
      Production Year: 1962
    - 当我们年轻的时候（保加利亚）, 1962 February 3 (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·席列茨科娃
    - 神童（西德）, 1962 February 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: K·霍夫曼
    - 北大荒人, 1962 March 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 崔嵬、陈怀皑
    - 祖国的黎明（朝鲜）, 1962 March 10 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 全东民
    - 歌唱家达尔克列（罗马尼亚）, 1962 May 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 约郭帕
    - 圣地亚哥之行（智利）, 1962 May 15 (Box 1)
      Film Director: H·古利亚
    - 拖拉机的驾驶, 1962 July 1 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 李句秀
    - 渴望（罗马尼亚）, 1962 August 13 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·德莱干
    - 青春的故事（苏联）, 1962 September (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·斯捷潘诺夫
    - 猎狗的故事（匈牙利）, 1962 September 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 侬斯特万
    - 盲人音乐家（苏联）, 1962 October (Box 1)
      Film Director: 润马诺夫斯基
    - 他们在战斗（阿尔巴尼亚）, 1962 October (Box 1)
      Film Director: H·阿卡尼
    - 这支枪留给你（苏联）, 1962 October (Box 1)
      Film Director: E·斯卡奇柯
    - 勇敢的胡安娜（墨西哥）, 1962 November (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·莎卡里亚士
    - 奇妙的"人", 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 3
      Film Director: 丛硕文
    - 斜面, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 4
      Film Director: 周彦、陈冀
    - 人工繁殖家鱼, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 6
      Film Director: 郑小秋
    - 奇峰异洞, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 8
    - 松林里的战斗, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 9
    - 知识老人, 1962 (Box 1)
      No.10
      Film Director: 杜生华
    - 他们的新课题, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 13
      Film Director: 王为光
    - 巧裁缝, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 15
    - 光合作用（捷克斯洛伐克）, 1962 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·贝尔纳得
    - 蔬菜栽培（保加利亚）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 12
      Film Director: 刘别恩、依昂契夫
    - 生命之线（保加利亚）, 1962 (Box 1)
      No. 16
      Film Director: 达那依诺夫
    - 韩江花似锦, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 谭友六
    - 王茂生进酒 (Box 1)
    - 复兴（阿尔巴尼亚）, 1963 (Box 1)
      No. 5
      Film Director: 恩德里·凯科
    - 锻炼（阿尔巴尼亚）, 1963 (Box 1)
    - 复活（下集）(苏联）, 1963 February (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·叶维茨尔
    - 红叶题诗, 1963 February (Box 1)
      Film Director: 张客
    - 炉火正红, 1963 February (Box 1)
      Film Director: 严恭
    - 军乐（匈牙利）, 1963 February (Box 1)
      Film Director: E·马尔敦
    - 士兵的经历（英国）, 1963 March (Box 1)
      Film Director: J·波尔丁
    - 红色宣传员（朝鲜）, 1963 April (Box 1)
      Film Director: 朴鹤
    - 水稻看苗追肥, 1963 May (Box 1)
    - 中锋在黎明前死去（阿根廷）, 1963 May (Box 1)
      Film Director: B·姆契卡
    - 蓝色港湾的船长们（苏联）, 1963 June (Box 1)
      Film Director: A·库罗奇金、A·托尔布津
    - 时代的凯歌（朝鲜）, 1963 August (Box 1)
      Film Director: 千尚仁
    - 工厂是我的大学（朝鲜）, 1963 August (Box 1)
    - 宝葫芦的秘密, 1963 December (Box 1)
      Production Year: 1963
    - 金色的海螺, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 万古蟾
    - 写好毛笔字, 1963 (Box 1)
    - 柴油机的清洁, 1963 (Box 1)
      No. 11
    - 苏联的"科学与技术"1963年第八辑（苏联） (Box 1)
      No. 17
    - 摩擦, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 石梅音
    - 木头变衣料, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 王君壮
    - 机床, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 葛德、鲍肖然
    - 怎么收藏红薯, 1963 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 郭鸿章
    - 光辉的历程 (Box 1)
    - 寂静的线索（波兰）, 1964 January (Box 1)
      Film Director: Z·古斯尼斯基
    - 春燕展翅, 1964 January (Box 1)
      Film Director: 李恩杰、马尔路
    - 防止渠道渗透, 1964 March 4 (Box 1)
    - 防止马鼻疽病, 1964 March 23 (Box 1)
      Production Year: 1964
    - 牛郎织女, 1964 April (Box 1)
    - 不屈的越南南方佛教徒（越南）, 1964 April 8 (Box 1)
    - 治虫早知道, 1964 May 15 (Box 1)
    - 革命历史歌曲表演唱, 1964 June 2 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 华纯
    - 库图佐夫将军（苏联）, 1964 June 8 (Box 1)
      Film Director: M·椰果诺夫
      Production Year: 1943
    - 民族英雄突多尔（罗马尼亚）, 1964 August 1 (Box 1)
    - 甘薯顿水顿火高温育苗, 1964 August 18 (Box 1)
    - 消灭羊疥癣, 1964 August 20 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 杨杰亭
    - 并肩前进（中国、阿尔及利亚联合摄制）, 1964 August 25 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 郝玉生、恩德列·凯戈
    - 光辉的节日——一九六四年国庆, 1964 October 26 (Box 1)
    - 恢复了名字的人（朝鲜）, 1964 September 14 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 全云峰、尹孝卓
    - 箭杆河边, 1964 November (Box 1)
      Film Director: 许珂、马尔路
    - 英雄儿女, 1964 December (Box 1)
    - 盐碱地上巧种麦, 1964 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 朱角
    - 1964年"科学与技术"第一号 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 沈沉
    - 防治苜蓿虫害（匈牙利）, 1964 (Box 1)
      Film Director: K·马尔顿
    - 蜘蛛（匈牙利）, 1964 (Box 1)
      No. 7
    - 什么是计量, 1964 (Box 1)
    - 保护青蛙, 1964 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 韩韦
    - 水面庄稼, 1964 (Box 1)
      No. 24
    - 二黑二黄, 1964 (Box 1)
      No. 25
      Film Director: 王为光、殷培龙
    - 对虾, 1964 (Box 1)
    - 盐碱洼地的好绿肥——田菁, 1965 March (Box 1)
      Production Year: 1965
    - 怎么计划生育, 1965 March (Box 1)
    - 科技简报 第一辑, 1965 May 10 (Box 1)
    - 红花遍地开, 1965 June (Box 1)
    - 暴风骤雨, 1965 September 5 (Box 1)
      Film Director: 谢铁骊
    - 牢记阶级仇, 1965 September 5 (Box 1)
    - 前进中的新疆, 1965 September (Box 1)
    - 北京农业的大跃进, 1965 November (Box 1)
    - 预防蛔虫病, 1965 November (Box 1)
      Film Director: 李甸秀
    - 苦菜花, 1965 December (Box 1)
      Film Director: 李昴
    - 柜台, 1965 December (Box 1)
      Film Director: 殷子
    - 1965年科学与技术简报第三辑 (Box 1)
    - 1965年科学与技术简报第二辑 (Box 1)
    - 中华人民共和国第二届运动会, 1965 November (Box 1)
    - 农村饮水卫生, 1965 (Box 1)